A Guide to the Max Oser films FA266
Rockefeller Archive Center
Max Oser films
1928-1940
Rockefeller Archive Center
Oser, Max
FA266
6 Cubic Feet 45 individual films, in 400 ft canisters. 45 access copy DVDs.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 48 business hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may require creation of an access surrogate. Applicable charges will apply.
Scope and Contents
45 black-and-white films shot by the Oser Family in the 1920s-1940s. The films are silent, unedited travelogues with footage from around the world. Several members of the Rockefeller Family make appearences in various films, as well as footage at different Rockefeller homes.
Arrangement
Chronological.
- Max Oser Film 1, 1928-1929; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes (Reel AV 1018)
  Scope and Contents
  Inter-tribal Indian ceremonial gathering in Gallup, New Mexico.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access copy available.
- Max Oser Film 2, 1929-1930; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes (Reel AV 1019)
  Gallup, New Mexico: Inter-tribal Indian cemetary (continued). Pendleton Indian parade.
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1019.
- Max Oser Film 3, 1930; 16mm film; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes (Reel AV 1020)
  Rodeo, parade, and Indian camp in Pendleton, New Mexico.
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1020.
- Max Oser Film 4, 1928-1929; 16mm motion picture film, 420 feet.; Sound, Black and white, 11 minutes (Reel AV 1021)
  Santa Barbara fiesta; cow/horse competition; zeppelin; Santa Ana/Orange County Fair; Warner Brothers locations in Laguna; Stanford football game; San Diego battleships; fishing in Florida
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1021.
- Max Oser Film 5, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 12 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1022)
  Arizona: Biltmore rodeo in Phoenix; Santa Barbara: polo (with Argentine team); Old Spanish Days celebration; July 4th parade
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1022.
- Max Oser Film 6, 1929; Silent, Black & white, 11 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1023)
  Capistano; San Fernando; 17-mile drive along Monterey; Yosemite; Mariposa
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1023.
- Max Oser Film 7, 1929; Silent, Black & White, 10 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1024)
  Sequoia National Park; Aqua Caliente; Palm Springs canyons
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1024.
- Max Oser Film 8, 1929-1930; Silent, Black & White, 11 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1025)
  Imperial Valley; Alligator Farm; Fort Marion, St. Augustine FL; Royal Palm State Park; Key West; Tamani Trail, etc.; Ormond Beach; Kissimmee; Bock Tower
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1025.
- Max Oser Film 9, 1930; Silent, Black & White, 10 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1026)
  Ormond Beach FL; New Orleans; Tesuque, Arizona; Santa Clara, Puye, Rio Grande; San Ilefonso
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1026.
- Max Oser Film 10, 1930; Silent, Black & White, 10 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1027)
  New Mexico: Santa Fe, Lamy, Santo Domingo, San Filipe, Mt. Taylor; Arizona: Apache Trail, Roosevelt Dam, Tonto Cliffs, Natural Bridge, Prince Crossing, Clear Creek, Verde River.
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1027.
- Max Oser Film 11, 1930; Silent, Black & White, 10 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1028)
  Arizona: Montezuma's Castle and well; rances in California and Arizona; Tempe Indian village
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1028.
- Max Oser Film 12, 1930; 16mm film; Silent, Black & white, 12 minutes. (Reel AV 1029)
  Arizona: Canyon Lake; California: Ojai Valley, Santa Barbara (Biltmore & Montecito); Sandiland; Gaviote Pass.
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1029.
- Max Oser Film 13, 1930; Silent, Black & White, 10 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1030)
  San Francisco; Portland; Seattle; Rainier National Park; Columbia River Highway
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1030.
- Max Oser Film 14 (1931 Trip I), Silent, Black & White, 11 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1031)
  Gallup; Chicago; Stockyard Parade; Fort Dearborn; Dick Wooten's ranch; frijoles; Rio Grand; San Ildefonso; Cyrus Ranch; Don Emilio Ramero; Nambe; Cundigo; Rio Chissta; Cordoba; Truors Sanctuario; Santa Fe; Rinconado; Taos
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1031.
- Max Oser Film 15 (1931 Trip II), Silent, Black & White, 10 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1032)
  El Oritz Lamy - Petrified Forest - Winslow Ariz - Painted Desert - Nevada Country - buttes - Walpi -2nd - Mesa - Lone Tree -Waterwell - Omibi - Hautevilla - Big Hogan - Coal Canyon - Tube Hogans - Dinosaur Tracks - Grand Canyon region - Hopi House - Indian Ruins - Desert - Maricopa - (Pime Post) - Hopi
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1032.
- Max Oser Film 16 (1931 Trip III), Silent, Black & White, 10 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1033)
  Grand Canyon - Hermit Pt - Yavapai - Winslow Rodeo - Keams Canyon - Canyon de Chelly - Casa Blanca - Wash near Polacca - Tewa - Sichamoui - Walpi - Hopi Reservation - Canyon de Chelly - Kayente - Azancoz Mesa - Monument Valley - Navaho Reservation
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1033.
- Max Oser Film 17 (1931 Trip IV), Silent, Black & White, 7 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1034)
  Navaho Reservation - Monument Valley - Kayenta - Mopsh Pass - Shanto - Rainbow Trail - Rainbow Trail - Nat. Bridge - Rainbow Trail - Redlake - Tomalea Waterhole - Elephant Feet - Moenkopi - Frisco AK - Meteor Cr. - Diving
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1034.
- Max Oser Film 18 (Egypt 1934 I), Silent, Black & White, 11 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1035)
  Nile, Asyut - Baliana - Erg Hamadi - Locks - Kalabsha (Nubia) - Natives - Assuan Races - Kirschner Il. - Gudera - Temples of Karnak - Assuan, Nile - Codfu - Lybian Desert - Ramambo - Philae - Shallel-End from Purchased "Aegean"
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1035.
- Max Oser Film 19 (Egypt 1934 II), Silent, Black & White, 11 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1036)
  Luxor + Races - Temples of Colorai - Isna - Luxor + Colossi - Karnak market - Geza market - Ourderuai - zoo - Nile near Cairo - Pyramid camp - Purchased "Luxor"
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1036.
- Max Oser Film 20 (Egypt 1934 III), Silent, Black & White, 11 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1037)
  Wadi Haifa - Abu Simbel - Khartoum - Flooded Nile around 2nd Cataract - Abu Simbel + Kasilbrim - Old Cairo - Cairo + zoo - Pyramids - Traffic Jam - "Arts + Crafts"
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1037.
- Max Oser Film 21 (1935 Trip I), Silent, Black & White, 10 minutes.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1038)
  Cairo: Empress of Britain - Bombay - Train - Delhi - Agra + Taj Mahal - Akbar's + Itmad's Tombs (Agra Region)
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1038.
- Max Oser Film 22 (1935 Trip II), Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1039)
  India: Agra - Benares from Ganges - Calcutta - Mountains -Darjeeling - Elephants - Dances
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1039.
- Max Oser Film 23 (1935 Trip III), Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1040)
  India: Madras - Madeina - Calombo - Perrang - Ankhar - Candlelight Dance - Bangkor - River Dwelling - Dances - Java
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1040.
- Max Oser Film 24 (1935 Trip IV), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1041)
  Bali: Dances - Phillipines: Dances - Manila - Hong Kong - Shanghai - Great Wall of China
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1041.
- Max Oser Film 25 (1935 Trip V), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1042)
  Peking - Kobe + Kioto (from Round Temple) - Japan (from black spot) - Hawaii - Hulas - Panama Canal
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1042.
- Max Oser Film 26 (1936 Trip I), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1043)
  Havana Capitol - Dutch West Indies (?) - Haiti - Martinique - Trinidad - Granada - Panama Canal - Christobal - Cocos Isle - Galapagos - Honolulu: school + departure
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1043.
- Max Oser Film 27 (1936 Trip II), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1044)
  Tahiti - Bora Bora - Dance - Apia (Fiji) - Dances - Pango Pango - Dance - Apia - islands - Dances
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1044.
- Max Oser Film 28 (1936 Trip III), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1045)
  Papua (Brit. New Guinea) Dances - NIAS - Dances - Hilo (?) - Bali - Java
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1045.
- Max Oser Film 29 (1936 Trip IV), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1046)
  Sumatra - Maquesars Nuruhive - Hiva Ga- Nias - Ceylon - elephants
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1046.
- Max Oser Film 30 (1936 Trip V), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1047)
  Ceylon - Seychelles - Madagascar - South Africa - St. Helena - Liberia - Dances - Maroc - Madeina
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1047.
- Max Oser Film 31 (Mexico 1937 I), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1048)
  Xochimilco Pyramids - Guernavaca - Azcapotzalco - Acapacingo - Maximilian's Bungalows - Acapulco - Chilpancinga - Texco - Mexico City - Bull fight
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1048.
- Max Oser Film 32 (Mexico 1937 II), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1049)
  Ixtapan de La Sal + region (horse trip) - Guatla - Xalitzintla - Oaxaca - Santo Domingo - La Soledad - Aqueduct - Monte Albena - Cartes Manor - Market
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1049.
- Max Oser Film 33 (Mexico 1937 III), Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1050)
  Ancient Stone - Bullock Carts - Las Animas - Cordoba - Orizaba - Puebla - Bullfight - Texacola - Mexico City region - Boca Raton (?)
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1050.
- Max Oser Film 34, 1928-1929; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1051)
  Lakewood N.J. - Anita, Peter, Pat, Muriel; Chicago - A. Blaine, Stanley, Harold, etc., Santa Barbara - Laguna Beach - Dr. Faville, Harold etc.
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1051.
- Max Oser Film 35, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1052)
  Laguna Beach - family - Harold + Seattle Osers; Agua Caliente - Pat + Parrots; Ormond Beach - fam. J.D.R. Mrs. E (Dr. Sheppard, Dr. Vincent), Nelson, the Clarks, the Whites
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1052.
- Max Oser Film 36, 1930; Silent, Black and white, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1053)
  Ormond Beach - J.D.R. family etc; The Casements - Golf Hole 8, etc; Mr + Mrs Stone - Dr. Brooks - Mr. White; Max - Dr. Brooks fishing
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1053.
- Max Oser Film 37, 1940; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1054)
  Casitas Ranch - fam. Romaine Lowdermilk; Arizona Biltmore - Phoenix (Desert) - Superstition Mountain – riding-Romaine Lowdermilk; Hayne Houses, St. Barbara - Easter etc.; Grank Island Neb. - Fam + Fowler - Tito + Louie
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1054.
- Max Oser Film 38, 1930-1931; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1055)
  Santa Barbara - Hayne House + Biltmore Hotel - P. Birthday, Easter, A's Birthday etc; Juan y Lolita Ranch Swimming; Byway Goat Ranch - Janet Hall & Family
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1055.
- Max Oser Film 39, 1931-1935; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1056)
  California 1931 - Point Dume - Coast Highway - Monterey - Carmel - San Juan - Barone - Navaho + Hopi Country - "Wallabee kangaroos"; 1935 Mission - (?) - Golden Gate - Monterey + region
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1056.
- Max Oser Film 40 (May and October 1931), 1931-1937; Silent, Black and white, 11 minute; 16mm film (Reel AV 1057)
  Diving + swimming contest Santa Barbara Biltmore; 1936 - Honolulu Army Parade; 1937 - Memorial Day Graceland Chicago
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1057.
- Max Oser Film 41, 1932-1935; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1058)
  California (Allister McC ? etc) - Pocantico Hills - J.D.R. etc - SS Bremen - Capt. Ziegenbein, etc - France 1934 - Egypt - (?); 1935 - India - Bali - Peking - Boat - Manila - California (Allister McC. + fam.)
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1058.
- Max Oser Film 42, 1935-1937; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1059)
  Empress of Britain 1936; 'The Casements' - J.D.R. - On "Stella Polares" - Panama Canal - Martinique - Bali - Hilo - South Africa (Noons); 1937 - Chicago - Memorial Day H. F. McC etc. - New Orleans - Harold + girls - Mexico
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1059.
- Max Oser Film 43 (Miscellaneous), 1932-1937; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1060)
  Clipper ship from Havana 1936 - Mississippi River Cruise + New Orleans 1937 - Tacoma River Cruise 1936 - Miami Chicago flight 1935 - Washington DC, Mount Vernon 1932 - England 1935 - Genoa, Naples + Capri 1934.
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1060.
- Max Oser Film 44, 1934-1935; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1061)
  Monte Carlo - Napoli (1935) - Jerusalem - Suez – Cairo; Palestine, Damascus - Beyrouth - Istanbul (1934)
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1061.
- Max Oser Film 45 (Near East), 1934; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1062)
  1934 Baulbuk - Beyrouth - Nazareth - Tiberius -Capernaine - Damascus – Jerusalem - Constantinople (?)
  Access copy available. Please request DVD AV 1062.